<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <bookinfo>
    <title>Specification of Gather the senders</title>

    <author>
      <firstname>Fabien</firstname>

      <surname>Arcellier</surname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname></orgname>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <pubdate></pubdate>
  </bookinfo>

  <chapter>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <section>
      <title>What is Gather the senders</title>

      <para>Gather the senders is an add-on for the mail client Thunderbird.
      It helps user to have a better productivity when they manage their
      emails.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Features</title>

      <para>Gather the sender has following features :</para>

      <para><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select all mails in the working directory sent by the same
            senders from mails already selected.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>

      <para><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Select all the emails in the working directory received by
            one of the reciptient present in emails already selected</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Futur</title>

      <para>To add new option on this add-on, it is possible to develop
      following features :</para>

      <para><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Improve the feature Gather the recipients</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Programming conventions</title>

    <para></para>

    <section>
      <title>Packages on Gather The Senders</title>

      <para>The domain of this add-on is gatherTheSenders.</para>

      <para>Every features should be include in subpackages of
      gatherTheSenders.</para>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Variables</title>

      <section>
        <title>Local variables</title>

        <para>Local variables are used in several place. Prefers the use of
        local variables in place of global as soon as possible</para>

        <section>
          <title>In a static function</title>

          <para>Declare the variable before the assertion, you can initiate
          variables when you declare them.</para>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Global variables</title>

        <para>We do not currently use global variables in this extension. If
        you have to, set them in the subpackages
        gatherTheSenders.globals</para>

        <para>Global variable have to be prefixed with g.</para>

        <example>
          <title>Exemple : Global variables</title>

          <para>gatherTheSenders.globals.gVersion,
          gatherTheSenders.globals.gHeaderParser</para>
        </example>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Debug mode</title>

      <para>When the debug mode is active, the functions from the package
      gatherTheSenders.debug are actives. You can these functions to display
      information in Thunderbird's console during the execution. To active the
      debug mode, set gatherTheSenders.debug.debug at TRUE</para>

      <para><table>
          <title>Reference of gatherTheSenders.debug</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Function prototype</entry>

                <entry>Explanation</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>dump([string] message)</entry>

                <entry>Display a message in Thunderbird's console during the
                execution (An implicit conversion can be done if another type
                than string is transfered, in place to display information
                message, it will display a warning. We advise to convert your
                type yourself before to give them as a param to this
                function)</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>assert([bool] exp, [string] message)</entry>

                <entry>Display a message in Thunderbird's console if a boolean
                expression return false. (An implicit conversion of message
                var can be done, in place to display information message in
                the console, it will display a warning. We advise you to
                convert message var by yourself if the type is different from
                string)</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>

      <section>
        <title>Assertion</title>

        <para>During the execution, you can verify the execution logic is what
        you are waiting. These assertions will help the tester to verify the
        extension works properly. Here are some examples what you can assert
        :</para>

        <example>
          <title>Examples of good assertion</title>

          <para>Final selection has not items than the original
          selection</para>
        </example>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <appendix>
    <title>Add-on testing</title>

    <para>To maintain a high-quality level for this add-on, it's very
    important to follow the test processus.</para>

    <para></para>

    <section>
      <title>Functionnal testing</title>

      <para></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Unit testing</title>

      <para>Developers has to write unit testing on his code. We use
      JsTestDriver coupled with Firefox to execute unit test.</para>

      <para>If you would like more information how to execute unit-test, go to
      Appendix B : Setup his environment.</para>
    </section>
  </appendix>

  <appendix>
    <title>Working environment</title>

    <para></para>
  </appendix>
</book>
